Guide to the Allen Ginsberg papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1943-1982
  - Stevenson, Adlai to Ginsberg, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Trilling, Lionel to Ginsberg, 1945-1950 (13 letters) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Trilling, Lionel to Ginsberg, 1951-1966 (11 letters) (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Van Doren, Mark to Ginsberg Undated
    - Undated, 1944-1949 (8 letters) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - 1950-1969 (8 letters) (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Villa, Jose Garcia to Ginsberg, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Williams, Florence Herman to Ginsberg, 1951-1964 (5 letters) (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Williams, William Carlos
    - to Ginsberg, 1956-1957 (10 letters) (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - to Louis Ginsberg, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - to Various Recipients, 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Wilson, Edmund to Ginsberg, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Zukofsky, Louis to Ginsberg, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Various Authors to Ginsberg, 1960s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 1 to 2)
    (letters and poems sent to Ginsberg by admirers)
  - Various Ginsberg Correspondence and Envelopes (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Series II: Writings and Manuscripts, 1950-1974
  This series includes manuscripts of writing both by Ginsberg and by his friends and collaborators, including the manuscript for Ginsberg's Indian Journals and the galleys for Howl and Other Poems. There are a number of Gregory Corso's poetry manuscripts as well as some poems by Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Michael McClure, and some examples of Jack Kerouac's poetry and prose, including a scroll that includes a partial draft of Mexico City Blues.
  Of particular interest and importance in this series is William S. Burroughs's "Interzone" manuscript-- the working title of what was later published as Naked Lunch. The manuscript was submitted to City Lights Publishing, but rejected and returned to Allen Ginsberg who was acting as Burroughs's literary agent.
  - Ball, Gordon-- Allen Verbatim, 1974
    - Proofs, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Manuscript (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Manuscript, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Page Proofs (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell-- "Epitaph for Maxwell Bodenheim" and "The Rose," undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Burroughs, William S.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16, Folder 5)
      (envelopes and fliers)
    - Copies of Mayan Codices, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Cut-ups and Fragments, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 7 to 8)
    - "Deposition: Testimony Concerning a Sickness," 1959 September (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "The Exterminator" Manuscript Sections, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      (includes sections entitled "The Algebra of Need," "The Black Meat," "Coke Bugs," and "The Exterminator Does a Good Job")
    - "The Hot Rod" manuscript, 1953, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 3 to 4)
    - "Interzone" manuscript, 1958 (Box 27)
      (manuscript for the novel that would be published under the title Naked Lunch. Includes corrections in Ginsberg's hand)
    - Pen and Ink Portraits, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Spontaneous Manifesto- CIA," undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Cassady, Neal-- Reading List, 1947 March (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - City Lights Books-- Ginsberg's Royalty Statements, 1952-1962 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    (for Howl and Other Poems, and Kaddish and Other Poems)
  - Committee on Poetry-- Statement in Favor of Lenny Bruce (Box 17, Folder 9)
    (includes sogned photograph of Lenny Bruce)
  - Colbert, Alison-- Interview with Ginsberg, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Corso, Gregory
    - Poems, undated
      - "After Reading H.G. Wells" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Army" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Birthday's End" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Compensation K. OOOO" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "D. Scarletti" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Dialogo- 2 Muñequeros" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Eastside Incidents" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Escape" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "For V.R. Lang" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Henry V" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "The House on the Door" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "In Memory of Flower-Cat" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "In Mexico" (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - "Letter to a Lady" (Box 17, Folder 12)
        (to Ruth Roman)
      - "Middleton's Gardens" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Mythicize the Adam…" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "October Transformation" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "On first Working with Rhyming Dictionary" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Pot" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Power" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Random Writings, Fiesole & Geneva 1960" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Think this return of your and Bruce's earn…" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Thoughts" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Thoughts While Walking Down Masonic Street" (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Was New York… and Now" (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Items (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Creeley, Robert-- poem-- "The Messengers: for Allen Ginsberg," [1964] (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Eberhart, Richard-- poem-- "Marrakech," 1965 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence-- Poetry Manuscripts
    - "After the Cries of the Birds has Stopped" (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Four Fugitive Configurations," 1966 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "The Man Who Rode Away," 1962 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Moscow in the Wilderness," 1967 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "White House Automat,"1968 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Ginsberg, Allen
    - "Ankor Wat," 1965 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      (composition from Journals. Xerox of poem with Ginsberg's footnotes and annotations and editorial marks by Stuart Montgomery of Fulcrum Press)
    - "At nineteen I was a cocksucker…" (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Composition from Journals, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      (Photostats with corrections)
    - "Documents on Police Bureaucracy's Conspiracy Against Human Rights of Opium Addicts…," 1970 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - "Entematious Poetry Encarnation" (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - "Excerpts. For the Novel. Jack to Lucien," 1944 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Howl and Other Poems-- Galley Proof (Folder Oversize Folder)
      (with Lawrence Ferlinghetti's Corrections)
    - Index for Kerouac's Mexico City Blues (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Indian Journals
      - Dedication, 1968, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 1 to 2)
        (typed, with corrections)
      - Excerpt, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Manuscript, circa 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        (typescript copy of Ginsberg's handwritten journals, with handwritten corrections)
      - Galley Proofs, 1968, (3 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 5 to 7)
        (corrected by Ginsberg and Dave Haselwood)
      - List of Corrections, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Page Proofs (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Kaddish
      - Dust Jacket Copy, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Fragments, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        (typescript with corrections in Ginsberg's hand)
    - "Kansas City to St. Louis" page proof (Box 19, Folder 3)
      (corrections in Ginsberg's hand)
    - "Message II", 1965, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Notebook, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      (contains interview notes, Czech vocabulary and addresses, and drafts of the poem "The Red Roller Coaster")
    - Notes on a conversation between Allen Ginsberg, Jack Kerouac, Bob Donlin, Timothy Leary, and Pearl, 1961 January 13 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Notes and Lists regarding Philip Whalen's Poetry, circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Plastic Asbestos" (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Publication Announcement for Burroughs's Junkie (Box 19, Folder 10)
      (draft)
    - "Squeak" (Box 19, Folder 11)
      (carbon copy)
    - "To an Old Poet in Peru," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      (typescript with corrections)
    - "Who be Kind To," 1965 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Fragments (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Ginsberg, Louis
    - Comments on Poems of Allen Ginsberg's, circa 1950 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - List of Publications (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Poems
      - "Office-worker," [1968] (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - "The Pause," 1966 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Jones, Ted-- "Black Flower," 1967 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    (mimeograph, inscribed to Ginsberg)
  - Kerouac, Jack
    - "Claude" (Box 19, Folder 19)
      (notes copied by Ginsberg)
    - Poetry Manuscripts
      - "Abraham Drinking Water," circa 1958 (Box 19, Folder 20)
        (with poem "To Bill" on the reverse)
      - "Auro boralis shomoheen…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "The Buddhist saints are incomparable saints…," circa 1956 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Daydreams for Ginsberg," 1955 February 10 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "The diamond that cuts through…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Example of My Blues," 1955 June 28 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Haiku Form" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "He is your friend, let him dream…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Hello fair friend, thy virtue for an hour…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Hey listen you poetry audiences…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Jamac! Jamac! ..." (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Long Dead's Longevity" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Me that was eyed…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Oh the mystery of this, the sweetness…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
        (with Ginsberg's notes on the reverse)
      - "Old buddy aint you gonna stay by me…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "One was called Boston Kitty…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "San Francisco has no vaults…" (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - "Some Western Haikus" (Box 19, Folder 20)
        (for Fernanda Pivano's Anthology)
    - Prose Manuscripts
      - "The Beat Generation" (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "Dave," circa 1954 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "A Dream Already Ended," circa May 1954 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "The Little Sutra," 1955 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Mexico City Blues-- Selected Choruses from
        - Original Typed Scroll (Box 27)
          (restricted use due to the fragility of the scroll. Please use photocopy)
        - Copy of the Scroll (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "A Prayer Towards Satori," 1955 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Prose Fragments and Notes (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "Some of the Dharma" (Box 19, Folder 21)
        (includes a note to Ginsberg)
      - From "Sutra Spoken by the Sixth Patriarch," 1954 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - The Town and the City-- inserts (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - "Une Petite Drâme," 1944 November 14 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Documents and a To-Do List (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Assignation of Power of Attorney to Allen Ginsberg, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - McClure, Michael
    - "Chessman," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "For Anger," 1965 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      (poem, with corrections and Ginsberg's notes)
    - "He and She," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "I Michael McClure," 1963 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Light Brown Ode to God," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Rembrandt," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "The screen is red & gold & white & pink…," 1966 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Smile Ode," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Son of Smile Ode," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - 'There is no Time of Love in Pain of Love or Faces in the Air," 1959 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "To Science," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Vishnu Carved at Mammalapuram," 1960 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Pivano, Fernanda Sotsass-- "la Favola di Ginsberg," 1965 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    (Article from Il Moda. Includes a summary in English)
  - Rodman, Selden-- "I give you these lines…" (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Rubin, Barbara-- Open Letter regarding a Performance at Royal Albert Hall, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Zukofsky, Louis-- "A" Libretto (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Inventories and Lists (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Series III: Artwork and Photographs, 1961-1968 and Undated
  This series is comprised of drawings and sketched executed by Ginsberg and his friends. There are also a small number of photographs of Ginsberg in this series.
  - Drawings
    - Burroughs, William S.-- Self-portrait (Folder Oversize Folder)
      (ink sketch)
    - Corso, Gregory
      - Hesitant Smile of Virgin Mary with Bill Burroughs in Her Arms (Box 20, Folder 1)
        (includes sketched of Allen Ginsberg, Jack Kerouac, and Joan Burroughs)
      - Robinson Crusoe Admiring the Stars (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Tanger, 1961 June 27 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Kerouac, Jack
      - Allen Ginsberg and William S. Burroughs, circa 1964 (Folder Oversize Folder)
        (pencil sketch-- with landscape ink sketch on reverse)
      - Allen Ginsberg and William S. Burroughs, circa 1964 (Folder Oversize Folder)
        (with ink sketch "Three Aged Trees" on reverse)
      - Ashpur, (Pencil Sketch) (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Crucifix, (pencil and crayon sketch) (Folder Oversize Folder)
      - [Drawing], (Ink Sketch) (Folder Oversize Folder)
      - [Drawing], (Crayon Sketch) (Folder Oversize Folder)
      - Laf by Jack (Box 20, Folder 3)
        (Drawing of Lafcadio Orlovsky)
    - Ginsberg, Allen
      - Buddha Footprint (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Tibetan Wheel of Life, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Photographs
    - Ginsberg-- Photographs from (Indian Journals) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Ginsberg (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Photographs Taken by Phyllis Segura (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Sound Recordings and Recording Projects, 1967-1971
  This series is comprised of records relating to Ginsberg's audio recordings with Barry Miles on the Zapple label. Most of the documents in this series relate to the planning and recording of Gnsberg's "Songs of Innocence and Experience by William Blake, Tuned by Allen Ginsberg."
  There are also two audio reels in this series, one of Ginsberg performing the poems of William Blake and a recording of an interview with Ginsberg wherein he talks about the hallucinogenic visions of Blake that he has while a college student in New York.
  - Recording Projects
    - Allen Ginsberg Collected Poems Vocalized
      - Contracts and Agreements, 1967-1970 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Notes and Memos, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Allen Ginsberg: Blake/Mantra II-- Notes, Memos, etc., 1969-1971 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Songs of Innocence and Experience, by William Blake, Tuned by Allen Ginsberg
      - Correspondence, Contracts, etc. 1968-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Notes, Correspondence, Musical Score, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Ginsberg Reading and Singing the Poems of William Blake, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Interview with Ginsberg, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      (regarding the hallucinatory visions of William Blake Ginsberg had while a student at Columbia)
  - Video Recording (Box 26, Folder 4)
    (cassette labeled "Chautauqua"-- is a recording of a stage show including dramatic readings of Walt Whitman and interpretive dances)
- Series V: Printed Material, 1956-1991
  The Printed Material series is comprised primarily of small literary magazines and newsletters that were either collected by Allen Ginsberg, include his work, or include articles or biographical sketches about him. Included are examples of the Poetry Project Newsletter and issues of Unmuzzled Ox. There are a small number of books owned by or with contributions by Ginsberg, most notable the first edition of Howl and Other Poems published by City Lights in 1954.
  - Articles, Newsletters, and Miscellany sent to Ginsberg by Fans (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit Announcements, Event Invitations, and Catalogs, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Publishers' Catalogs, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Literary Magazines Owned by Ginsberg (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals and Articles owned by Ginsberg, 1983-1990 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    (including issues of the Poetry Project Newsletter)
  - Periodicals owned by Ginsberg (Box 21, Folder 8)
    (with inscriptions or notes)
  - Naropa Institute Material, 1977-1987 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    (course catalogs, etc.)
  - Printed Material and Articles About Ginsberg, 1970-1991, (5 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Printed Material with Contributions by Ginsberg, 1969-1991, (5 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Printed Material with Contributions by Ginsberg, 1969-1991, (4 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Books
    - With Contributions by Ginsberg (Box 25)
    - Howl and Other Poems (Box 25)
      (First Edition, City Lights Publishing)
    - Books Presented to Ginsberg, (3 Folders) (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Books (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 2 to 4)